phoenixts.com 2019-10-05

# Privacy Policy | Phoenix TS

UPDATED July 10, 2018

Thank you for visiting us online at PhoenixTS.com. At Phoenix Technology Solutions, LLC d/b/a Phoenix TS, we strive to do everything we can to respect the trust customers have in our brand.Our commitment to your privacy is no exception. We are committed to protecting and safeguarding consumer privacy on the Internet. This Privacy and Cookie Policy  (the “Policy”) applies to the Phoenix TS website, the Phoenix TS Portal and Learning Management Solution (“LMS”), as well as the Phoenix TS Electronic Training Management System (“ETM”). The Policy governs data collection and usage. This policy becomes effective immediately for all visitors, previous and new by using the Phoenix TS website, you consent to the data practices described the Policy.. Thanks again for visiting our website and for placing your trust in Phoenix TS.

## Collection of Your Personal Information

Phoenix TS may collect personally identifiable information, such as name, your e-mail address, home or work address or telephone number. Phoenix TS may also collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that may be automatically collected by Phoenix TS. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information may be used by Phoenix TS for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Phoenix TS website.

Phoenix TS collects name, company and contact information including email address and uses this information internally for registration, transcript management, payment, and other purposes. In addition, course evaluations completed by you on the Phoenix TS website may be viewed by Phoenix TS management, the course trainer, and other people as deemed necessary. The course evaluations may be used for marketing purposes, after removing  any and all personally identifiable information.

In addition, Phoenix TS may collect information from social media sites, such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, etc. Those social media sites may give Phoenix TS _automatic access_ to certain personal information retained by them about you, including by not limited to content viewed by you, content liked by you, and information about the advertisements you have been shown or have clicked, etc. You control the personal information you allow us to have access to through the privacy settings on the applicable social media site and the permissions you give Phoenix TS when you grant us access to the personal information retained by the respective social media site about you. By associating your personal social media accounts with the Phoenix TS social media pages you are authorizing us to have access to this information, you agree that we can collect, use and retain the information provided by these social media sites in accordance with this privacy notice. We may also use plugins or other technologies from various social media sites on any other Phoenix TS websites. If you click on a link provided via a social media plugin, you are voluntarily establishing a connection with that respective social media site.

## Use of Your Personal Information

Phoenix TS may collect and use your personal information to operate the Phoenix TS website and deliver the services you have requested. Phoenix TS also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Phoenix TS and its affiliates. Phoenix TS may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. Phoenix TS may share your personally identifiable information with third parties to perform services on our behalf. This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly solicit or collect personally identifiable information from children.

Phoenix TS does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Phoenix TS may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, Phoenix TS may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, provide training services or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Phoenix TS, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Phoenix TS does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Phoenix TS keeps track of the websites and pages our customers visit within Phoenix TS, in order to determine what Phoenix TS services are the most popular. This data may be used to deliver customized content and advertising within Phoenix TS to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Phoenix TS reserves the right to use or disclose any information as needed to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request, to protect the rights, property or integrity of Phoenix TS, to fulfill your requests, to cooperate in any law enforcement investigation or an investigation on a matter of public safety, or act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Phoenix TS, or the public.

## Security of Your Personal Information

Phoenix TS secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Phoenix TS secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to us or other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

### Access

You are in control of any personal information you provide to us online. If at any time, you would like to review any personal information we have about you or correct the personal information we have about you or if you would like to change your preferences for contacts from us or on behalf of our business partners, contact us at info@phoenixts.com.

Please note that Phoenix TS will never send you an email requesting your password or social security number. Phoenix TS may send you an email with a link to a payment page when a registration request has been sent to it. If you request to pay online, Phoenix TS may send you a link to a credit card acceptance form. If you receive an email that looks like it’s from Phoenix TS, but asks you for your password or social security number, it’s a fraudulent email, or “phish.” We recommend that you do the following:

Forward the email to the US Federal Trade Commission at spam@uce.gov or call 1-877-FTC-HELP (1-877-382-4357) to report it. The FTC uses the spam stored in this database to pursue law enforcement actions against people who send deceptive email. Delete the email.

If you believe “phishers” have gotten access to your personal or financial information, we recommend that you also do the following:

Change your password. Contact credit reporting services (such as Experian, Callcredit and Equifax) and have a fraud alert attached to your credit report file. Please be aware that the perpetrator may attempt to use your information to establish accounts or obtain credit at other businesses in their name.

## Use of Cookies

Like most websites, Phoenix TS uses cookies for a variety of purposes in order to improve and help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. There are several different types of cookies and the Phoenix TS website uses all of them; necessary cookies, performance cookies, and preference cookies.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Phoenix TS pages, or register with Phoenix TS site or services, a cookie helps Phoenix TS to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Phoenix TS website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Phoenix TS features that you customized.

Cookies are stored for different lengths of time depending on the type of cookie. Persistent cookies stay on your device indefinitely until the expire or are deleted by you. Session cookies only stay on your device until you have ended your browsing session.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Phoenix TS services or websites you visit.

If you use different devices to view and access websites (e.g., your computer, smartphone, tablet) you will need to ensure that each browser on each device is adjusted to suit your cookie preferences

The procedures for changing your settings and cookies differ from browser to browser. If necessary, use the help function on your browser or click on one of the links below to go directly to the user manual for your browser.

You can find out a great deal of additional information about cookie settings at third-party sites, such as [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Information On Message Boards

Please note that public message boards do not currently exist on Phoenix TS websites but may be added in the future.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Phoenix TS public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: Phoenix TS does not read any of your private online communications. 

### Third Party Websites

Phoenix TS encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Phoenix TS so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. 

Phoenix TS is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Phoenix TS and Phoenix TS family of websites. Please note that public message boards do not currently exist on Phoenix TS websites but may be added in the future.

### Links To Other Sites

Phoenix TS may offer links to sites that are not operated by Phoenix TS. If you visit one of these linked sites, you should review their privacy and other policies. We are not responsible for the policies and practices of other companies, and any information you submit to those companies is subject to their privacy policies.

## Changes To Privacy Statement

Phoenix TS will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect company and customer feedback. Phoenix TS encourages you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to be informed of how Phoenix TS is protecting your information.

## Contact Information

This is a United States website and is subject to laws of the United States and the State of Maryland.

Phoenix TS welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. If you have any questions about our Phoenix TS privacy policy, please contact us at info@phoenixts.com.
